Joey Chan UX Designer | UX Researcher | UX Developer

(65) 90269772 I joeychan149@gmail.com I linkedin.com/in/joeychan149/ I joeychan149.medium.com/ I behance.net/joeychan8 I Singaporean

SUMMARY

I am a relentless problem solver with 6 years marketing experience. I am skilled in UX, social media, web and writing skills. I have boosted Meiji Facebook from zero to a few thousand followers. It led to smooth transition of the online selling platform expanding to 3rd party Qoo Gmarket online selling, and increased sales by 10% and customer awareness by 30%. My goal as a UX practitioner is to create user friendly web or mobile apps and improve web traffic while making it life easier for the users.

CORE SKILLS

UX & Design: UI Design, User Research, Heuristic evaluation, Wireframing, Prototyping, User Journey Map Programming: Javascript, ReactJs, HTML, CSS, Github, Visual Studio Code, ATOM, Notepad++, Python, NPM, NodeJS, Git, GitLab, NextJS, Android Studio, Jquery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, ChartJS.
Tool & Platforms: Figma, Adobe Invision, XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, CMS, Webflow, Mailchimp, Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, Brackets, Wordpress, Drupal, Constant Contact, Behance, Medium
Others: Empathetic, Curiosity and passion for testing new ideas, creative and resourceful, a keen eye for aesthetics and details, regional.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

User Experience Design

- Healthy365 Mobile App: The project aims to improve the process of rewards redemption through exercising. I have worked on the User Flow and UI Design of the proposed solution.
- Shuttle Partner Mobile App: It is a Bangladesh based transport system seeking to recruit and attract driver signups. We have improved the user flow and I am currently working on the prototyping.

Digital Marketing

- Developed Facebook campaigns for Meiji which helped to increase its online sales by 30%.
- Redesigned product ranges and managed outdoor sales events which resulted in 5% increase in sales.
- Relationship management with Amino Collagen members and ensured the stickiness of the members.
- Tracked competitors' movements and designed strategies to improve and increase sales for Meiji and Konica Minolta.
- Set up various digital campaigns for Darlie including Facebook, google analytics analysis for various regions and countries. Managed and monitored web traffic and social media activities.
- Planned and executed sales award activities, which has motivated sales staff to boost sales.

Project Administration/ Management & Data Management

- Managed project schedule and created resource utilisation report for IT projects to ensure projects are run on time and on schedule.
- Information (delivery orders) & Data management via report generation to ensure good tracking records to reflect the contract status.
- Implemented system improvements for shipping so that the system runs more efficiently

Client Servicing

• Sourced new product categories by reaching out to overseas suppliers to increase sales and revenue.

Joey Chan UX Designer | UX Researcher | UX Developer

(65) 90269772 I joeychan149@gmail.com I linkedin.com/in/joeychan149/ I joeychan149.medium.com/ I behance.net/joeychan8 I Singaporean

- Functioned as purchasing and buying in the commodity market so that the categories can bring in more revenue.
- Conducted product review before entering the actual market and discovered market potential.
- Procurement on quality of items, review of Indirect Purchase process for payment to reestablish the
 whole system process integration so that the various departments can get support smoothly on
 Accounts Payable issues.
- Negotiated prices on marketing collaterals and resulted in cost savings for Meiji and Ocean Network Express by 10%.

Links to my design portfolio and Figma redesigns

behance.net/joeychan8

https://joeychan149.medium.com/

https://joey147.github.io/Breadandbutter/index.html

https://www.figma.com/file/pD7K2ePDLSrzrU1pFmjNdX/Pet-Mobile-App?node-id=0%3A1

https://www.figma.com/file/sKy5mzjvtGg4VoNJUMTdlk/Website-Redesign?node-id=20%3A2

https://www.figma.com/file/3suxc50jVSBWbpUunYR4on/Fwd-Insurance?node-id=0%3A1

https://www.figma.com/file/kf13GKGVVeXVKAz72ZuBsB/ConnectedLife-Health?node-id=0%3A1

https://joey147.github.io/EonReality/

https://breadandbutter.vercel.app/

https://joey147.github.io/Chart-JS/

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

International Sourcing Team Leader | NTUC Fairprice Pte Ltd | Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

Project Administrator | Silverlakegroup Pte Ltd | Nov 2018 - Feb 2019

Executive | Ocean Network Express Pte Ltd | Oct 2017 – Jun 2018

Marketing Executive | MJI Universal Pte Ltd | Mar 2016 - Oct 2016

Marketing Executive I Genufood Enzymes (S) Pte Ltd I Jul 2013 - Apr 2014

Marketing Assistant | Darlie Toothpaste and Toothbrush | Mar 2012 - Jan 2013

Marketing Executive | Meiji Seika Singapore Pte Ltd | Sep 2009 – Mar 2012

Marketing Executive I Konica Minolta Business Solutions (S) Pte Ltd I Jul 2008 – Jul 2009

Trade Marketing Assistant I Jia Jia Sales and Marketing Pte Ltd I Sep 2007 - Jul 2008

Secretary | Fujitsu Asia Pte Ltd | May 2006 - Jul 2007

Call Agent I Onasus / Itech Vision I Apr 2004 - May 2006

Administrator I EMC Asia Pacific Pte Ltd I Jan 2003 - Jan 2004

Customer Service Officer / Systems Analyst | Maersk Singapore / Logistics Asia Pte Ltd | Dec 2000 – Apr 2002

EDUCATION

Codigo and Sandbox basics for HTML, CSS and Javascript NTU University Jun 2021 - July 2021

UX DESIGN AND PRODUCT MANAGEMENT I NTU University I Dec 2020 - Jun 2021

Cybint Cyber Security Protection I NTUC Learning Hub I Sep 2020

Certified Scrum Product Owner I Theanthropy Pte Ltd I Aug 2020

Project Management for All I NTUC Learning Hub I Jul 2020

Project Fundamentals using Gantt Chart I NTUC Learning Hub I Jul 2020

Comparing Agile vs Waterfall Project Management I NTUC Learning Hub I Jul 2020

Know your customers through Human Centered Approach I NTUC Learning Hub I Jul 2020

Adobe Photoshop Essentials I Skills Global Academy I Aug 2018

Diploma in Marketing (distinction) I Ngee Ann Polytechnic I Jul 1998 – Jun 2000

Joey Chan
UX Designer | UX Researcher | UX Developer
(65) 90269772 I joeychan149@gmail.com I linkedin.com/in/joeychan149/ I joeychan149.medium.com/ I behance.net/joeychan8 I Singaporean

LANGUAGE

English, Chinese, Japanese (Pre-advanced JLPT 3), Korean (Basic)